# ALLSTON SCHWARTZ

Charleston, South Carolina 29407 | (843) 224-8492

# **PROFILE**

Though I've worked in multiple disciplines, my focus lies in front-end development and interaction design. I have a passion for solving problems, constantly perfecting my craft, and producing work that I can be proud of. I'm currently seeing to expand my skills in a software development role, so if you're interested in hiring me, check out my work, and let's get in touch.

### **EDUCATION**

## The Iron Yard. / Frontend Developer

January 2015 - March 2015

12 week intensive Frontend Development program

Charleston, SC

# Georgia State University

August 1995 - May 1998

BA in English Literature and a minor in Theatre Arts (GPA 3.75)

Atlanta, Ga

**SKILLS** 

PROGRAMMING: HTML 5

CSS3/SASS

Javascript

**jQuery** 

Angular

Backbone

Underscore

TOOLS:

Command Line

Version Control

**AJAX** Bower/NPM

**DESIGN:** 

**Bootstrap** 

Git/Github

CMS:

WordPress

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Addlestone Hebrew Academy**

Teaching Assistant

Charleston, SC

Feb 2013 - Jan 2015

- Created recorded text for students with language based learning disorders
- Conducted small group and individual classroom activities with students based on differentiated learning needs to ensure all students are learning at full potential.
- Participated on ongoing staff training sessions.
- Organized parent-teacher conferences to maximize student learning opportunities and develop forward-thing plans to correct ongoing issues.
- Employed assessment tools and proactive strategies to improve instruction methods.
- Assisted in producing curriculum that met state goals as well as meeting the needs of the individual students
- Worked with groups ranging from as little as 6 to as large as 30

#### Inside the Envelope

CEO/Invitation Consultant

Charleston, SC Oct 2008 - Present

- Expertise in areas ranging from business administration to marketing invitations and creative services
- Entrepreneur who through effective business planning, creative sales techniques, and innovative marketing, cultivated relationships with clients and vendors that garnered continued business and positive referrals
- Recognized by clients and colleagues as a consummate professional with a high degree of personal integrity.
- Known for a contagious passion for excellence, ensuring consistent quality customer service to internal and external clients and attainment of individual and team goals.

RONT END DEVELOPER